# JEREMIAH MARTIN

UH-60M Blackhawk Helicopter Repairer 7174068009

#### ∘ DETAILS ∘

7174068009 jeremiahmartin117@gmail.com

o SKILLS o

Mechanical

Detail oriented

Computer proficient

Self driven

Willingness to learn

Adept multi-tasker

Team Orientated

Promptness

Positive attitude

**Customer Service** 

#### ∘ HOBBIES ∘

Skiing, Oil painting, Computer building, Wood working, Metal working/ Blacksmithing, Reading

#### PROFILE

I served 6 years in the US Army as a Blackhawk mechanic and crew chief. With over 650 flight hours, I have learned how to communicate effective and timely. Having deployed to Afghanistan, traveled to Romania, Germany and all across the US, I am use to all environments. Being an aircraft mechanic as taught me to operate and use a high level of precision. During that time, keeping aircraft flying and safe was my number one priority. At the same time, I was also a Squad Leader. As a Squad Leader I would supervise between 4 to 10 other mechanics. Taking care of any problems they had, as well as guiding and teaching them, helping them grow as aircraft mechanics. Before my time as an aircraft mechanic, during high school I also worked as a stocker in a local grocery store for about 4 years. I learned how to balance school work as well as a part time job. Since honorably separating from the Army, I am attending collage as well as working at PaulB wholesale in shipping and receiving.

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

# Stocker at Oregon Dairy, Lancaster

2010 - 2013

During my time at this position I was tasked with stocking shelves, and maintaining a clean work environment. As well as assisting customers, taking inventory and assisting managers order new stock.

# Field Worker at Pioneer Hi-Bred International, New Holland

2010 - 2013

In this summer seasonal job I would pollinate corn plants. It would require a high level of detail to make sure parts of the pant were not missed.

## UH-60M Blackhawk Helicopter Repairer at US Army

June 2013 - Present

Duties included, maintaining, repairing and replacing parts. Often, referring to detailed technical maintenance manuals during tasks to ensure correct maintenance. Overseeing all maintenance tasks of the day, and supervising maintainers to ensure completed of correct work. Reporting progress and solutions to problems to my supervisors during daily meetings.

# Warehouse Associate at PaulB Wholesale, Lancaster

June 2019 - August 2019

Receiving, inspecting and putting away product. Ensuring proper loading of trucks. Driving fork lifts and man lifts. Loading and unloading trucks, as well as racking pallets. Conducting inventories on a daily biases.

### EDUCATION

# Spartan college of Aeronautics and Technology, Tulsa, Ok

March 2018 - Present

Degree: Airframe and Powertrain License

This is a hybrid program that is part online, allowing me to work full time, and in the 2019 fall semester begin the on ground, hands on training. This license will empower me to have the skills and knowledge to fix and maintain all type of aircraft. Upon completion of this course I will be perusing an associations degree as well as furthering my aviation training.

# Conestoga Valley High School, Lancaster, PA

2009 - 2013

Degree: High School Diploma

## REFERENCES

SGT Mike Bales from US Army

mike.bales17@tcu.edu | 2164699746

Mr. Phil Groff from Paul B. Zimmerman

philsharon1994@gmail.com | 4845991887

1SGT Justin Hutchison from US Army

justin.d.hutchison.mil@mail.mil | 9073883662

CW2 Megyn-Lea Thompson from US ARMY

thompsonmc.22@gmail.com | 6158187516

Rob Hackman from PaulB Wholesale

robhackman@pbz.com | 8557381117